1. Request a secret code, used to prove age.
2. The provider calculates the following (which will be saved on the database, the secret code is only known to the user who requested it):
EncryptedAge = HASH ^ (ActualAge + 1)(S)
That is, run a chain of the hash (the output of the first round is the input of the second round and so on) function on the input one time greater than the user's age.
3. In order to prove that the user is older than AgeToProve, the following action will take place:
3.1. The user will calculate the following:
Proof = HASH ^ (1 + ActualAge − AgeToProve)(S)
3.2. Whoever wishes to check whether the user is older than AgeToProve, will calculate the following:
VerifiedAge = HASH ^ AgeToProve(Proof)
and then check if VerifiedAge = EncryptedAge